CURRICULUM VITAE

Name: Jantsje Maria Mol, MSc.

Date of birth: 17-08-1990

Address: E7.30, Roetersstraat 11, 1018 WB Amsterdam

E-mail: j.m.mol@uva.nl
Website: www.jantsje.nl



I am a postdoctoral researcher at CREED, the Center for Research in Experimental Economics and political Decision making of the University of Amsterdam. My main interests are experimental economics and behavioral economics. Currently, I am working in the team of Shaul Shalvi on a project studying the importance of trust in the sharing economy.

I have a research master in Neuroeconomics from Maastricht University, with a particular focus on experimental economics and behavioral economics. My PhD supervisors are Wouter Botzen and Julia Blasch. My PhD project aimed to improve individual flood-preparedness by finding the determinants of individual decisions to invest in flood damage mitigation measures. I expect to defend my dissertation in Summer 2021.

PUBLICATIONS

- Bloemendaal, N., de Moel, H., **Mol, J. M**., Bosma, P. R. M., Polen, A. N., & Collins, J. M. (2021). Adequately reflecting the severity of tropical cyclones using the new Tropical Cyclone Severity Scale. *Environmental Research Letters*, *16*(1), 014048. https://doi.org/10.1088/1748-9326/abd131
- **Mol, J.M.**, Botzen, W.J.W., Blasch, J.E., (2020). Behavioral motivations for self-insurance under different disaster risk insurance schemes. *Journal of Economic Behavior and Organization*, 180, 967-991, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jebo.2018.12.007
- Mol, J. M., Botzen, W. J. W., Blasch, J. E., Kranzler, E. C., and Kunreuther, H. C. (2020). All by myself? Testing descriptive social norm-nudges to increase flood preparedness among homeowners. https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.3616189 (revise & resubmit)
- **Mol, J. M**., Botzen, W. J. W., Blasch, J. E., and de Moel, H. (2020). Insights into flood risk misperceptions of homeowners in the Dutch river delta. *Risk Analysis*. https://doi.org/10.1111/risa.13479
- **Mol, J.M.**, van der Heijden, E.C.M., Potters, J.J.M., (2020). (Not) alone in the world: Cheating in the presence of a virtual observer. *Experimental Economics*. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10683-020-09644-0
- Mol, J. M., Botzen, W. J. W., and Blasch, J. E. (2020). Risk reduction in compulsory disaster insurance: Experimental evidence on moral hazard and financial incentives. *Journal of Behavioral and Experimental Economics*, 84 (February 2020), 101500 https://doi.org/10.1016/j.socec.2019.101500
- **Mol, J.M.**, (2019). Goggles in the lab: Economic experiments in immersive virtual environments. *Journal of Behavioral and Experimental Economics*, 79(C), 155-164. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.socec.2019.02.007

EDUCATION	
2016 – 2021	PhD in behavioral economics of natural disaster risk Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam Institute for Environmental Studies, department of Environmental Economics
2014 – 2016	Research visit Risk Management and Decision Processes Center, Wharton School, University of Pennsylvania Master of Science in Cognitive & Clinical Neuroscience (Research Master) Maastricht University Track: Neuroeconomics.
2011 – 2014	Internship: Economic Experiments in Virtual Reality, Tilburg University, grade 9/10 Bachelor of Science Tilburg University Liberal Arts & Sciences. Major: Social Sciences. Graduated cum laude.

Semester abroad at Nanyang Technological University, Singapore

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Teaching Assistant

2016 – present Environmental Economics (Master level), Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam

Teaching evaluations 2019: 4.22/5 Teaching evaluations 2018: 4.10/5

2018 – present Statistics in R (practical, Master level), Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam

Theses supervision

L. Braconi, Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam, MSc.
 A. Carvallo, Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam, MSc.
 A. Molenaar, Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam, BSc.

Lecturer

Dec 2019, 2020 Guest lecture on Experimental Economics, *Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam*Mar 2018 Guest lecture on Experimental Economics, *Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam*oTree Workshop for PhDs and Faculty, *Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam*

Nov 2017 oTree Workshop for PhDs and Faculty, Tilburg University

SEMINAR AND CONFERENCE PRESENTATIONS

2020 - ESA 2020 Global Around-The-Clock-Meetings (online)

- SABE 2020 (online)

- BIT (behavioral insights team) webinar (invited)

(for policy makers at the Ministry of Infrastructure and Water Management)

5th Workshop on Experimental Economics for the Environment, Universität Heidelberg (poster)

2019 - Norms and Behavioral Change Workshop, University of Pennsylvania (poster)

BEEMA5. Villanova

- SPUDM, Amsterdam (poster) - Runner up Best Poster Award

WINK Nudging and Beyond, Utrecht University

- European conference on risk perception, Université de Cergy Pontoise, Paris (invited)

2018 - CEAR/MRIC Behavioral Insurance Workshop, Munich

ESA World Meeting, Berlin

- 3rd Workshop on Experimental Economics for the Environment, Universität Hamburg

BEEC, Universidad del Rosario, Bogotá (poster)

2017 - VR for experimental economics workshop, RWTH Aachen (invited)

TIBER Symposium, Tilburg University

- CREED lunch seminar, University of Amsterdam

SKILLS

Languages: Dutch: native

English: fluent

German, Spanish, French: basic

Software skills: R, Stata, SPSS, Microsoft Office, oTree, Adobe Creative Suite: advanced

MATLAB, HTML, Django, Python, JavaScript, ArcGIS Pro: intermediate